<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on prinzpiuz</title>
    <link>/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on prinzpiuz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2023, prinzpiuz</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:43:47 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Async Django</title>
      <link>/post/introduction-to-async-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:43:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introduction-to-async-django/</guid>
      <description>This is a written version of the talk I presented to my colleagues. This is a basic introduction to asynchronous programming in django. So the async support for django came with django 3.1 in august 2020, a great leap in the history of Django. still, it lacks support in certain areas like ORM, and cache layer, but it will be available soon. The effort for implementing async support in django was done by Andrew Godwin 👏 Now let&amp;rsquo;s look into how this async django works&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Errors and Exceptions In Python</title>
      <link>/post/errors-and-exceptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 17:46:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/errors-and-exceptions/</guid>
      <description>This blog is about How to manage Exceptions in python, this is more like notes I took while reading Dusty Phillips&amp;rsquo;s Python 3 Object-oriented Programming, This post can be divided into
 why raise an exception? what is happening when an exception is raised? Handling exceptions The exception hierarchy Defining our exceptions  Why raise an exception? All the programs out there don&amp;rsquo;t always output a valid result, errors can happen like it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to divide by zero, or to access the eighth item in a five-item list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Saves My Time</title>
      <link>/post/python-saves-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:20:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/python-saves-time/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Repetitive task should be automated&amp;rdquo; - somebody, somewhere 😎
 Its common philosophy in the field of it to automate repetitive tasks, even if it takes some time now to set up it will save a lot of time in the future. In this post, I like to share the kinda experience I had today while updating my machine and how python solved it easily.
In my work machine, I am running Manjaro Linux, which is a Rolling Release based on Archlinux.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
