<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on prinzpiuz</title>
    <link>https://prinzpiuz.in/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on prinzpiuz</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2024, prinzpiuz</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 10:40:46 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://prinzpiuz.in/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Clone Your Machine to Another</title>
      <link>https://prinzpiuz.in/post/how-to-clone-your-machine-to-another/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 20:24:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prinzpiuz.in/post/how-to-clone-your-machine-to-another/</guid>
      <description>Context Recently my primary workstation failed due to a motherboard issue. I needed to quickly get my development environment setup on another machine. Here are the steps I followed to clone my machine using rsync. Before moving on to that, Let me explain a little about rsync, In layman&amp;rsquo;s terms rsync is a utility for efficiently transferring and synchronizing files between a computer and an external disk, it does this by sending only the differences in the data to the destination rather than resending the whole file every time there is an update.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Media Server Set-up</title>
      <link>https://prinzpiuz.in/post/my-media-server-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 14:58:35 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prinzpiuz.in/post/my-media-server-setup/</guid>
      <description>The reason I&amp;rsquo;m writing this blog because I learned lot of things while setting up my media server to current configuration, so this is kinda experience sharing, may be useful for those who trying one.&#xA;Little History &amp;#x1f55c; From my teenage itself I&amp;rsquo;m a binge movie watcher, at that time I saves money and buy DVDs of movies I like and I had a small collection of DVDs, then I brought a desktop PC, and it was time of USB sticks and it became little more easy and cheap to collect movies, still somebody need to download movies from torrent (thanks The Pirate Bay) or rip from DVDs,but still network speed was very low then(I had a BSNL bradband connection which had only 512kbps), With the arrival of 4G.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python Saves My Time</title>
      <link>https://prinzpiuz.in/post/python-saves-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:20:59 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://prinzpiuz.in/post/python-saves-time/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Repetitive task should be automated&amp;rdquo; - somebody, somewhere &amp;#x1f60e;&#xA;Its common philosophy in the field of it to automate repetitive tasks, even if it takes some time now to set up it will save a lot of time in the future. In this post, I like to share the kinda experience I had today while updating my machine and how python solved it easily.&#xA;In my work machine, I am running Manjaro Linux, which is a Rolling Release based on Archlinux.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
